<KEY>B,A,C,D,A,B,A,B,B,D,C,A,D,C,A,C,D,D,B,A,B,C,B,B,C,B,A,B,C,A,B,D,C,A,B,A,C,B,D,A,C,B,A,D,D,A,A,A,B,A,C,A,B,B,A,B,B,A,A,B,C,D,B,C,A,A,C,D,B,A,C,B,D,C,A,D,B,C,D,A,B,C,B,D,A,B,C,A,D,A,D,C,B,A,B,D,C,B,A,A</KEY>
<QUESTIONS>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>1. The word "Bible" means:</Q><A>A. Writing|B. All the books|C. Holy|D. Literature|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>2. The word "Scripture" means:</Q><A>A. Writing|B. All the books|C. Holy|D. Literature|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>3. The two major divisions of the Bible are:</Q><A>A. Prophecy and poetry|B. Gospels and epistles|C. Old and new testaments|D. Law and history|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>4. The number of books in the Bible:</Q><A>A. 39|B. 27|C. 64|D. 66|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>5. The number of books in the Old Testament:</Q><A>A. 39|B. 27|C. 64|D. 66|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>6. The number of books in the New Testament:</Q><A>A. 39|B. 27|C. 64|D. 66|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>7. The Old Testament books are divided into the following categories:</Q><A>A. Law, history, poetry, prophecy|B. Gospels, history, epistles, prophecy|C. Neither of these.|D. Both of these|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>8. The New Testament books are divided into the following categories:</Q><A>A. Law, history, poetry, prophecy|B. Gospels, history, epistles, prophecy|C. Neither of these.|D. Both of these|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>9. The word "testament" means:</Q><A>A. The books|B. Covenant|C. Writing|D. A plan|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>10. The purpose of the Bible includes:</Q><A>A. Doctrine|B. Correction|C. Instruction|D. All of these|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>11. The "unity of the Bible" means:</Q><A>A. It is united in content|B. It is united in theme|C. Both of these|D. Neither of these|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>12. The "diversity of the Bible" means:</Q><A>A. It has variety|B. It conflicts itself|C. It is united in content|D. Different men wrote it|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>13. The revelation of both Old and New Testaments is centered on:</Q><A>A. Satan|B. Man|C. Sin|D. Jesus Christ|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>14. The Bible is:</Q><A>A. Not divinely inspired|B. Similar to the Koran|C. The written Word of God|D. Just one of many divine manuscripts|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>15. A translation of the Bible:</Q><A>A. Translates word for word|B. Translates letter by letter|C. Translates thought by thought|D. None of these|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>16. A paraphrase of the Bible:</Q><A>A. Translates word for word|B. Translates letter by letter|C. Translates thought by thought|D. All of these|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>17. The word "version" means:</Q><A>A. The same as translation|B. Written in the same language as the original manuscript of the Bible|C. The same as paraphrase|D. Written in a language other than what the Bible was originally written|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>18. The languages in which the Bible was originally written include:</Q><A>A. Hebrew|B. Greek|C. Aramaic|D. All of these|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>19. Geography tells ___________ an event happened:</Q><A>A. When|B. Where|C. Why|D. How|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>20. History of chronology tells ___________ an event happened:</Q><A>A. When|B. Where|C. Why|D. How|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>21. Biblical archaeology is:</Q><A>A. The study of the future|B. The study of the past|C. The same as geography|D. None of these|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>22. The main points on an outline are normally indicated by:</Q><A>A. Abbreviations|B. Letters and numbers|C. Roman numerals|D. None of these|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>23. Sub points on an outline are indicated by:</Q><A>A. Abbreviations|B. Letters and numbers|C. Roman numerals|D. None of these|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>24. Which is the oldest date?</Q><A>A. 500 BC|B. 1000 BC|C. 2000 AD|D. 100 AD|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>25. The author of the first five books in the Bible was:</Q><A>A. Joshua|B. Abraham|C. Moses|D. Adam|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>26. Old Testament events occurred mostly in:</Q><A>A. China, Japan, Korea|B. Egypt, Canaan, Assyria|C. Spain Greece Italy|D. India, Malaysia, Egypt|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>27. The first five books of the Bible are called the books of:</Q><A>A. Law|B. History|C. Poetry|D. Prophecy|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>28. Joshua, Judges, Ruth, I and II Samuel, I and II Kings, I and II Chronicles, Ezra, Nehemiah and Esther are all books of:</Q><A>A. Law|B. History|C. Poetry|D. Prophecy|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>29. Job, Psalms, Proverbs, Ecclesiastes, and Song of Solomon are all books of:</Q><A>A. Law|B. History|C. Poetry|D. Prophecy|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>30. Isaiah, Jeremiah, Ezekiel, and Daniel are all books of:</Q><A>A. Major prophets|B. Minor prophets|C. Law|D. History|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q> 31. Hosea, Joel, Amos, Obadiah, Jonah, Micah, Nahum, Habakkuk, Zephaniah, Haggai, Zachariah, and Malachi are all books of:</Q><A>A. Major prophets|B. Minor prophets|C. Law|D. History|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>32. Match each event in List One to the correct geographical location: Name of the River Israel crossed to enter the Promised Land.      </Q><A>A. Ai|B. Jerusalem|C. Jericho|D. Jordan|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>33. Match each event in List One to the correct geographical location in List Two: The walls of this city fell down.                           </Q><A>A. Ai|B. Jerusalem|C. Jericho|D. Jordan|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>34. Match each event in List One to the correct geographical location in List Two: Israel was defeated in battle here.                     </Q><A>A. Ai|B. Jerusalem|C. Jericho|D. Jordan|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>35. Match each event in List One to the correct geographical location in List Two: Nehemiah rebuilt these walls.                      </Q><A>A. Ai|B. Jerusalem|C. Jericho|D. Jordan|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>36. Match each event in List One with the proper kingdom: The northern kingdom.                            </Q><A>A. Israel|B. Assyria|C. Judah|D. Babylonia|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>37. Match each event in List One with the proper kingdom: The southern kingdom.                           </Q><A>A. Israel|B. Assyria|C. Judah|D. Babylonia|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>38. Match each event in List One with the proper kingdom: Israel was taken into captivity by this nation.            </Q><A>A. Israel|B. Assyria|C. Judah|D. Babylonia|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>39. Match each event in List One with the proper kingdom: Judah was taken into captivity by this nation.           </Q><A>A. Israel|B. Assyria|C. Judah|D. Babylonia|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>40. We had 19 kings, all evil.</Q><A>A. Israel|B. Assyria|C. Judah|D. Babylonia|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>41. We had 20 kings; many evil, a few good.</Q><A>A. Israel|B. Assyria|C. Judah|D. Babylonia|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>42. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded:  Records the departure from Egypt and journey of Israel in the wilderness.</Q><A>A. Genesis|B. Exodus|C. Numbers|D. Deuteronomy|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>43. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: The book of beginnings.</Q><A>A. Genesis|B. Exodus|C. Numbers|D. Deuteronomy|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>44. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: The law restated by Moses before his death.</Q><A>A. Genesis|B. Exodus|C. Numbers|D. Deuteronomy|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>45. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: Final instructions before entering the Promised Land.</Q><A>A. Genesis|B. Exodus|C. Numbers|D. Deuteronomy|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>46. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: Contains the stories of Abraham, Isaac, Jacob, and Joseph.</Q><A>A. Genesis|B. Exodus|C. Numbers|D. Deuteronomy|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>47. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: Contains the first promise of the Redeemer who was to come to take away sins.</Q><A>A. Genesis|B. Exodus|C. Numbers|D. Deuteronomy|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>48. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: Records the fall of man.</Q><A>A. Genesis|B. Exodus|C. Numbers|D. Deuteronomy|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>49. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: Records the giving of the l0 commandments.</Q><A>A. Genesis|B. Exodus|C. Numbers|D. Deuteronomy|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>50. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: Tells the story of the great flood on the earth.</Q><A>A. Genesis|B. Exodus|C. Numbers|D. Deuteronomy|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>51. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: Contains the story of Israel coming to the border of the promised land, but NOT going in.</Q><A>A. Genesis|B. Exodus|C. Numbers|D. Deuteronomy|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>52. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: Contains the story of creation.</Q><A>A. Genesis|B. Exodus|C. Numbers|D. Deuteronomy|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>53. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: Israel leaves Egypt.</Q><A>A. Genesis|B. Exodus|C. Numbers|D. Deuteronomy|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>54. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: Tells about the first Passover.</Q><A>A. Genesis|B. Exodus|C. Numbers|D. Deuteronomy|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>55. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: Contains the story of the tower of Babel.</Q><A>A. Genesis|B. Exodus|C. Numbers|D. Deuteronomy|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>56. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: Tells about Mosses' birth and early life in Egypt.</Q><A>A. Genesis|B. Exodus|C. Numbers|D. Deuteronomy|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>57. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: Tells about the l0 plagues that came on Egypt.</Q><A>A. Genesis|B. Exodus|C. Numbers|D. Deuteronomy|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>58. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: This book tells the story of Cain and Abel.</Q><A>A. Genesis|B. Exodus|C. Numbers|D. Deuteronomy|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>59. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: Details how the successor of Moses led Israel into the promised Land of Canaan.</Q><A>A. Joshua|B. Judges|C. Ruth|D. I and II Samuel|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>60. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: This book records the repeated sins of Israel and the men and women God raised up to deliver them from enemy forces.</Q><A>A. Joshua|B. Judges|C. Ruth|D. I and II Samuel|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>61. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: The story of the woman who became the great grandmother of David.</Q><A>A. Joshua|B. Judges|C. Ruth|D. I and II Samuel|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>62. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: These books tell the stories of Samuel, Saul, and David.</Q><A>A. Joshua|B. Judges|C. Ruth|D. I and II Samuel|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>63. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: People are busy rebuilding the temple in this book.</Q><A>A. Kings and Chronicles|B. Ezra|C. Nehemiah|D. Job|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>64. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: People are busy rebuilding the walls of Jerusalem in this book.</Q><A>A. Kings and Chronicles|B. Ezra|C. Nehemiah|D. Job|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>65. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: Records of the kings and kingdoms.</Q><A>A. Kings and Chronicles|B. Ezra|C. Nehemiah|D. Job|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>66. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: The Jews were saved by the person for whom this book was named.</Q><A>A. Esther|B. Job|C. Psalms|D. Proverbs|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>67. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: The hymn book of the Bible.</Q><A>A. Esther|B. Job|C. Psalms|D. Proverbs|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>68. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: A collection of wise sayings.</Q><A>A. Esther|B. Job|C. Psalms|D. Proverbs|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>69. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: The story of a righteous man who suffered.</Q><A>A. Esther|B. Job|C. Psalms|D. Proverbs|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>70. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: Life without meaning is vanity.</Q><A>A. Ecclesiastes|B. Song Of Solomon|C. Daniel|D. Lamentations|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>71. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: Prophecy concerning the end times.</Q><A>A. Ecclesiastes|B. Song Of Solomon|C. Daniel|D. Lamentations|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>72. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: The bride and bridegroom.</Q><A>A. Ecclesiastes|B. Song Of Solomon|C. Daniel|D. Lamentations|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>73. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: Lament over the destruction of Jerusalem.</Q><A>A. Ecclesiastes|B. Song Of Solomon|C. Daniel|D. Lamentations|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>74. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: A prophet who preached to Nineveh.</Q><A>A. Hosea|B. Obadiah|C. Jonah|D. Zechariah|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>75. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: Israel is an unfaithful wife.</Q><A>A. Hosea|B. Obadiah|C. Jonah|D. Zechariah|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>76. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: Challenge to complete building the temple.</Q><A>A. Hosea|B. Obadiah|C. Jonah|D. Zechariah|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>77. Match each event to the Bible book in which it is recorded: Judgment against Edom.</Q><A>A. Hosea|B. Obadiah|C. Jonah|D. Zechariah|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>78. Match the person with the correct statement: I married Boaz.    </Q><A>A. Rebecca|B. Boaz|C. Ruth|D. Naomi|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>79. Match the person with the correct statement: I was mother-in-law to Ruth and Orphra. </Q><A>A. Rebecca|B. Boaz|C. Ruth|D. Naomi|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>80. Match the person with the correct statement: I was Isaac's bride.   </Q><A>A. Rebecca|B. Boaz|C. Ruth|D. Naomi|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>81. Match the person with the correct statement: I married Ruth.   </Q><A>A. Rebecca|B. Boaz|C. Ruth|D. Naomi|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>82. Match the person with the correct statement: I led Israel into the promised land.   </Q><A>A. Gibeonites|B. Achan|C. Joshua|D. Caleb|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>83. Match the person with the correct statement: I sinned by taking gold and a Babylonian garment.   </Q><A>A. Gibeonites|B. Achan|C. Joshua|D. Caleb|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>84. Match the person with the correct statement: I was very old, but still claimed a mountain for my inheritance.  </Q><A>A. Gibeonites|B. Achan|C. Joshua|D. Caleb|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>85. Match the person with the correct statement: We deceived Joshua so he would not destroy us.              </Q><A>A. Gibeonites|B. Achan|C. Joshua|D. Caleb|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>86. Match the person with the correct statement: God saved me because I hid the spies.       </Q><A>A. Saul|B. Rahab|C. Samuel|D. David|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>87. Match the person with the correct statement: I anointed both King Saul and King David.     </Q><A>A. Saul|B. Rahab|C. Samuel|D. David|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>88. Match the person with the correct statement: I was the first King of Israel.               </Q><A>A. Saul|B. Rahab|C. Samuel|D. David|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>89. Match the person with the correct statement: I committed a great sin with Bathsheba.        </Q><A>A. Saul|B. Rahab|C. Samuel|D. David|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>90. Match the person with the correct statement: I was a very close friend of David's.             </Q><A>A. Jonathan|B. Isaac|C. Deborah|D. Samson|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>91. Match the person with the correct statement: I lost my strength through compromise with sin.      </Q><A>A. Jonathan|B. Isaac|C. Deborah|D. Samson|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>92. Match the person with the correct statement: I am a woman who led an army of Israel to victory.    </Q><A>A. Jonathan|B. Isaac|C. Deborah|D. Samson|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>93. Match the person with the correct statement: I was the miracle son of Abraham.              </Q><A>A. Jonathan|B. Isaac|C. Deborah|D. Samson|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>94. Match the person with the correct statement. You may use an answer more than one time: I put out a fleece to test God's will        </Q><A>A. Gideon|B. Aaron|C. Balaam|D. Cain|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>95. Match the person with the correct statement. You may use an answer more than one time: I was the first high priest of Israel.          </Q><A>A. Gideon|B. Aaron|C. Balaam|D. Cain|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>96. Match the person with the correct statement. You may use an answer more than one time: I committed the first murder.             </Q><A>A. Gideon|B. Aaron|C. Balaam|D. Cain|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>97. Match the person with the correct statement. You may use an answer more than one time: My donkey spoke to me.                 </Q><A>A. Gideon|B. Aaron|C. Balaam|D. Cain|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>98. Match the person with the correct statement. You may use an answer more than one time: I led Israel in worship of the golden calf.</Q><A>A. Gideon|B. Aaron|C. Balaam|D. Cain|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>99. I completed reading the text for this course..</Q><A>A. True|B. False|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
<QUESTIONRECORD><Q>100. I completed the self-tests at the end of each chapter. </Q><A>A. True|B. False|</A></QUESTIONRECORD>
</QUESTIONS>
<COURSE>Old Testament Survey</COURSE>
<EOF></HTML>
